Narrator: 1
T: OK, so now repeat after me – du pain
SS: du pain
T: de la salade
SS: de la salade
T: des saucisses
SS: des saucisses
Narrator: 2
T: So last week we looked at percentages, and today we’re going to look at fractions.
Can someone give me an example of a fraction?
S: Er, three quarters?
T: Yes, exactly. And what would that be as a percentage?
S: 75%.
Narrator: 3
T: Can anybody tell me the dates of the First World War?
S: Oh, me sir, me sir!
T: Angela?
S: 1939 to 1945, sir.
T: No, that’s the Second World War.
Try again.
Narrator: 4
T: So we’re going to start by defining a few words and phrases.
I’m going to dictate the terms and I want you to write a short definition.
So, for example, if I said the word cookies, what would you write?
S1: Biscuits?
T: Very funny, Carl. Anna?
S2: Er, pieces of data that, er, websites put onto your computer?
T: That’s right. And what do internet cookies do?
S2: They record details of the websites you’ve visited and, er, how long you’ve spent on them.
Narrator: 5
T: OK, Act 3, scene 1. OK, Jack you can be Hamlet.
This is a very important speech. Are you ready?
S: Yes. To be or not to be, that is the question. Whether…
Narrator: 6
T: So I have a small piece of sodium here, about one cubic centimetre,
and we’re going to see what happens when we add it to water.
So if you could all stand back a bit…further back…OK…here we go…
Narrator: 7
T: Today, we’re going to look at two self-portraits from different centuries. Take a look at these.
S: The one on the right looks like you, sir!
T: Thank you, Jasper. Now I want you to start by thinking about two questions.
When do you think the self-portraits were painted?
And how old do you think the artists were when they painted them?
Narrator: 8
T: OK, we’re going to warm up first, I want you to run round the track three times.
SS: Can’t we play football?
T: No, come on, three times round the track. Ready, steady, go.
Narrator: 9
T: There are no active volcanoes in the UK, but there are quite a lot in the rest of Europe.
Can anyone tell me a European country that has active volcanoes?
S1: Erm, France?
T: Not France, no…
S2: Italy? Italy has Mount Etna.
T: Yes, Italy. In fact, Etna is the highest active volcano in Europe, at over 3,300 metres.